coffeepartyusa.com 2018-06-30

# Coffee Party Privacy Statement - CoffeeParty

**COFFEE PARTY USA PRIVACY POLICY**  

**Coffee Party USA (“Coffee Party”, "we", "us")  **is a District of Columbia 501 (c) 4 nonprofit organization. .

Like many ways we are connected on the internet, using and interacting with the Coffee Party website ("site") and the Join the Coffee Party Movement facebook page ("page") may provide us personal information.  Keeping this information secure is of key importance to the Coffee Party, and we are providing this privacy policy to clearly and transparently provide you information on what data we may keep, and how that data is used.  This is your personal data, and you deserve to know what information is used, how that information is used, and how you can opt-in and opt-out of the use of that information. This privacy policy provides the details of how the Coffee Party safeguards your personal information.

By using this site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and of the Terms of Use for this site, which can be found here: [http://www.coffeepartyusa.com/tos.](http://www.coffeepartyusa.com/tos)

**What Information We Collect**

Through the use of the site and/or page, the Coffee Party can acquire access to personal information provided directly or indirectly from you.  This information includes:

  * Name (First and Last)
  * Email Address
  * Phone Number 
  * Location (City, State, Country)
  * Social Media Platforms (Facebook, Twitter, etc.)
  * Information from Social Media Platforms (such as Marital Status, Declared Gender, etc)

This information is provided to the Coffee Party typically either through data you provide directly when creating an account for the site, or from information from facebook when interacting with our page.  Retweeting and reposting content from the Coffee Party's Twitter account may provide this information as well. In addition the site may use Google Analytics or other tracking cookies which may provide additional information which can be considered personal information including IP Address, Browser, and Operating System.

Purchases made through the site, including donations and membership, are handled through third party systems.  The information you provide is provided to [Stripe](https://stripe.com/) or [Paypal](https://www.paypal.com/) for purposes of the transaction. Information related to the purchase, including billing information, may be stored on the site to support the transaction.

**How We Use Your Information**

When you register, contribute, sign up to volunteer, or take any other action on our site, we may ask you to give us contact information, including your name, address, telephone number and/or e-mail address. We may obtain information about you from outside sources and add it to or combine it with the information we collect through this site. We use this information to operate this site, send news and information to you about the Coffee Party movement, solicit your participation in Coffee Party programs, membership, local events and activities, merchandise and obtain and confirm RSVP’s to events and programs. We use your e-mail address to send such information by e-mail and may use your telephone number to call you for these purposes.

We will never provide your e-mail address or any of your personal information to any other person or organization, for any purpose, except

  * to companies such as our web management service, NationBuilder, or our payment transaction services Paypal and Stripe, that assist us in maintaining this site or with Coffee Party activities, but only for purposes of providing services to Coffee Party and with the strict requirement that any such company will never itself have the right to contact you for any reason
  * to comply with applicable law or legal requirements (for example,, a lawful subpoena), to protect our rights or property, or to protect our supporters from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful conduct, or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records

Submitting your personal information including your e-mail address will sign you up to receive e-mails from the Coffee Party.

For petitions and surveys that you've signed or completed, we treat your name, city, state, and comments as public information - for example, we may provide compilations of petitions, with your comments, to elected officials and legislators, other targets, or to the press. We will not make your street address publicly available, but we may transmit it to elected officials or legislators as part of a petition. In no such case will we disclose your email address or phone number without your specific permission. We may also make your comments, along with your first name, city, and state available to the press and public online.

We may also use your first name to indicate the latest actions taken on this site.

#### Children

Coffee Party complies with the Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act. Coffee Party does not solicit and does not accept personally identifying information from any person under 13 years of age. Visitors to this site who are under 13 years of age should not use this site except under the supervision and with the assistance of their parent or legal guardian, and should never submit any personally identifying information to the site. For example, visitors under 13 years of age should not make donations or take any actions on or through this site.

**Credit Card Information; Protection of Personal Information**

When you purchase merchandise, materials or other items through this website, we collect credit card information from you. We do not receive or store credit card information in our database. That information is used for processing your contribution; is maintained by a third party such as Paypal or Stripe; and is never disclosed to anyone, for any other purpose other than for processing your contribution, under any circumstances.

Coffee Party uses industry standard security measures to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control. All supplied credit card information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our payment processing provider’s database. Permission to access your information is granted only to you and Coffee Party employees or contractors who need to know that information to provide services to you and who are required to keep the information confidential. Although we make good faith efforts to store information collected by this website in a secure operating environment, we cannot guarantee complete security.

#### Cookies and Data Tracking

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Some parts of this site may be password-protected. We may use a cookie (cookies reside on your computer and are under the control of your browser) to help us remember and process items that you purchase through this site; and/or to compile aggregate data about visitors to the site and their interaction with the site for the purposes of improving the operation of the site and/or offering better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use cookies to enable you to return to password-protected areas of the website without having to re-enter your password. You may choose to opt out of cookies, either by refusing consent for cookies on the website, or by disabling cookies through your browser setting, however, you may not be able to access certain parts of this site.

We may also use third-party services such as, but not limited to, Google Analytics. This helps us understand traffic patterns and know if there are problems with our website. We may also use embedded images in emails to track open rates for our mailings, so that we can tell which mailings appeal most to Coffee Party supporters.

#### Advertising

We may place online advertising with third-party vendors, including Google, which will be shown on other sites on the internet. In some cases, those third-party vendors may decide which ads to show you based on your prior visits to the site. At no time will you be personally identified to those third-party vendors, nor will any of the information you share with us be shared with those third-party vendors. If you prefer to opt out of the use of these third-party cookies on the site, you can do so by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**Links to Other Sites**

The privacy policies and practices contained in this Privacy Statement do not apply to ANY external links. This Privacy Statement only applies to our site or any future sites that we may develop. It does not cover sites that are linked to by this site or sites for which we are not responsible ("linked-sites"). These linked-sites will have their own policies and practices which may be different from ours. We therefore encourage you to familiarize yourself with the policies and practices of the linked-sites, especially if you provide personal information to them.

California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Coffee Party complies with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. As part of that Act, all users of our site may make any changes to their information at any time by logging into their Control Panel and going to the “Edit Profile” page. Changes to billing and/or credit card information must be made through Paypal or Stripe. Coffee Party USA staff can only cancel future transactions, not alter existing recurring contributions.  For more information or assistance, contact [info@CoffeePartyUSA.com](mailto:info@coffeepartyusa.com). 

**Amendments and Consent to This Privacy Statement**

By using our site, you consent to the collection and use of the information as we have described. If we change our policies and practices, we will post the changes in our Privacy Statement so that you are always aware of them. With this knowledge, you can make an informed decision about whether you wish to provide personal information to us.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, you may contact us by:

Coffee Party USA

PO Box 866

Corvallis, OR  97339
